Finding Aid for the Sierra Club Angeles Chapter Records LSC.1199
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sierra Club Angeles Chapter records
1917-2016
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sierra Club. Angeles Chapter
LSC.1199
110.5 linear feet (224 document boxes, 2 half document boxes, 2 oversize boxes)
8 born-digital carriers (21 floppy disks, 1 DVD, and 1 optical disc)
0.775 Gigabytes (152 files, 10 folders) Transferred from 1 optical disc.
4 born-digital carriers (2 optical discs, 2 floppy disks)
0.370 Gigabytes (173 files, 7 folders) Transferred off of 2 optical discs.
The Sierra Club branch in Los Angeles, California was founded by Phil Bernays and some fellow Sierrans in 1911. The Chapter originally provided leadership for hiking trips into the local mountains and High Sierra, and helped spread the word of John Muir. The collection consists of conservation issues and administration files including Southern California region minutes (1951-84), chapter newsletters and other publications, and assorted conservation issue materials related to the Sierra Club Angeles Chapter.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed digital materials. Digital materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Sierra Club Angeles Chapter, 1977-. The 2012 addition consisting of the Alice E. Knapp papers was transferred from UC Berkeley, Bancroft Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942337793606533
Biography
The Sierra Club is a nonprofit organization in the U.S. and Canada that works to promote and protect natural resources; it was founded in San Francisco (1892) by the naturalist John Muir who was the first president (1892-1914); by the late 20th century the club grew to an approximate 540,000 members; local chapters organize conferences, lectures, films, exhibits, and various expeditions; it publishes reports, magazines, books, and special publications and has numerous committees working to educate the public on environmental issues and lobbying local, state, and federal bodies for environmental legislation.
The Sierra Club branch in Los Angeles, California was founded by Phil Bernays and some fellow Sierrans in 1911; the Southern California Chapter, as it was originally known, stretched from San Luis Obispo to the Mexican border to the California desert; Muir Lodge in Big Santa Anita Canyon was Club headquarters from October 4, 1913 until its destruction in the great storm of 1938; the Chapter originally provided leadership for hiking trips into the local mountains and High Sierra and helped spread the word of John Muir.
Scope and Content
Collection consists primarily of material related to the Sierra Club Angeles Chapter. Includes conservation issues and administration files including Southern California region minutes (1951-84), chapter newsletters and other publications, and assorted conservation issue materials. Also includes newsletters published by various sections of the club.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
Sierra Club Oral History Project (Collection 329). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Collection of Ephemera Related to the Sierra Club (Collection 1197). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Environmental protection -- California, Southern.; Nature conservation -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Newsletters.; Sierra Club. Angeles Chapter--Archives.; Sierra Club. Angeles Chapter--History.
- Air Pollution
  - Air Pollution (Box 85, Folder 5-10)
  - 19/7c-8f. (Box 86, Folder 1-13)
  - 19/10-19/14. (Box 87, Folder 1-6)
  - 19/15-19/16. (Box 88, Folder 1-4)
- Alice E. Knapp personal papers, 1917-1984
  Scope and Content
  This series consists of 37 photo albums and scrapbooks compiled by Alice E. Knapp, containing items from 1917-1984, with the bulk of material from the early 1920s to mid 1930s. Albums primarily document her participation in Angeles Chapter activities, and feature a wealth of images of Southern California landscape and various chapter members. Also included in the albums are clippings from the chapter's outings schedule; annotations and typewritten narrative accounts; and a number of botanical samples. Approximately 7 albums are exclusively related to Knapp's personal life and her son Woolsey Ernest Knapp who was killed in WWII.
  Organization and Arrangement
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order by subject, reflecting the given album titles.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Some photos damaged by glue.
  - Arizona (Vol. 8), 1928 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Arrowhead, Big Bear, San Gorgonio, San Jacinto (Vol. 12), 1926-1933 (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Death Valley Duplicates, 1931-1936 (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - Dias de Antano, A Mi Hijo, 1930 (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - Family Album (Vol. 18), 1932-1939 (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - Hello, Mother! (Vol. 17), 1935-1938 (Box 191, Folder 3)
  - Last Chance, 29 Palms, Hayfields, Hidden Springs, Snow Creek, Local (Vol. 5), 1929-1930 (Box 192, Folder 1)
  - Lost City, Boulder Canyon, Death Valley, Las Vegas, 1931-1968 (Box 192, Folder 2)
  - The Memory Trail (Original Book 1), 1926-1934 (Box 193, Folder 1)
  - The Memory Trail (Original Book 2), 1931-1935 (Box 193, Folder 2)
  - The Memory Trail (Original Book 3), 1935-1936 (Box 193, Folder 3)
  - The Memory Trail I (Vol. 4), 1927-1931 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - The Memory Trail II (Vol. 4A), 1932-1933 (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - The Memory Trail III (Vol. 4B), 1933-1935 (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - The Memory Trail IV (Vol. 4C), 1935-1936 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - The Memory Trail V, 1936-1937 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  - Mi Hijo (Vol. 1), 1919-1925 (Box 196, Folder 2)
  - Mi Hijo II (Vol. 1A), 1925-1935 (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Mi Hijo III (Vol. 1B), 1920-1944 (Box 197, Folder 2)
  - My Desert Land I (Vol. 6), 1924-1934 (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - My Desert Land II (Vol. 6A), 1932 (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - My Desert Land III: Red Rock (Vol. 6B), 1922-1933 (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - My Desert Land IV (Vol. 6C), 1923-1933 (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - My Desert Land V, 1935 (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Ocean, San Diego, and vicinity; El Camino Real (Vol. 14 and 15), 1922-1934 (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Paso Robles (Vol. 19), 1920s-1930s (Box 200, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Eva L. Miller, 1949 (Box 200, Folder 3)
  - Salutaciones de Navidad (Vol. 3), 1922-1984 (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Scrap Book I (Vol. 13), 1921-1935 (Box 201, Folder 2)
    Contains copies of photos taken circa 1855-circa 1913, as well as original photos dating 1921-1935.
  - Scrap Book II (Vol. 13A), 1919-1936 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  - Sequoia, Post Pile, Old Mexico, San Diego, San Jacinto (Vol. 4), 1926-1935 (Box 202, Folder 2)
  - Sierras Altas (Vol. 10), 1924-1936 (Box 203, Folder 1)
  - Sierras Altas II (Vol. 10A), 1932 (Box 203, Folder 2)
  - Sierra Alta IV (Vol. 10C), 1929-1971 (Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Sierra Madre (Vol. 9), 1922-1933 (Box 204, Folder 2)
  - Sierra Madre II (Vol. 9A), 1933-1934 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 20 1917-[1960] (Box 205, Folder 2)
    Contains mostly unlabeled photos of people, construction, and farming.
  - The White Heart of Mojave, Death Valley, 1925-1969 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Sierra Club Knapp Collection File, 1994-2008 (Box 204, Folder 3)
- Angeles Chapter Financial Reports
  - Financial Statements, 1950s. (Box 144)
  - Binder labeled ?Angeles Chapter Treasurer's Records 1951 to present (1967?). (Box 144)
  - Financial Reports (Miscellaneous[?]). (Box 144)
  - Financial Reports, 1930s and 1940s. (Box 144)
  - Field Work Sheets (1950s[?]). (Box 144)
  - Financial Statements, Information, 1960s. (Box 145)
  - Financial Reports, 1970s. (Box 145)
- Angeles Chapter Items, Miscellaneous
  - Bylaws Revision, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photo, 1929. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Copies of The Grand Canyon Dams: A Brief Analysis by Richard H. Ball, a chapter publication, 1966. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sierra Club Membership Leaflet (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Angeles Chapter Membership Lists
  - Miscellaneous mailing lists from 1930s through early 1960s. (Box 148)
  - Computer outputs of membership addresses from late 1960s. (Box 148)
- Angeles Chapter Papers
  - Council, 1966-1961. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1965. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1968. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1962. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1969. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1970. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1971. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1972. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1973. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1974. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1977. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1978. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1982-88. (Box 144)
  - Binder containing Angeles Chapter Council minutes, 1971-77 and 1965-1966. (Box 144)
  - Conservation Committee (Angeles Chapter). (Box 144)
  - Ex-Com, 1977-1978 (Executive Committee Minutes). (Box 144)
  - Council, 1967. (Box 144)
  - Council, 1966. (Box 144)
  - Committee Reports, 1940s (Box 145)
  - Correspondence, V. Ferguson (Office Secretary), 1940s (Box 145)
  - Correspondence, Office, General, 1940s (Box 145)
  - Ski Mountaineers Treasurer's Report, 1940s (Box 145)
  - Unfiled financial reports, 1940s (Box 146)
  - Unfiled miscellaneous papers, 1940s (Box 146)
  - Membership, 1940s (Box 148)
- Assorted Conservation Materials, 1951-1964
  Scope and Contents note
  Including Clippings, Ephemera and Circular Letters
  - A - C. (Box 9)
    General note
    (Additions donated November 1978)
  - D - K/L. (Box 10)
  - La - S. (Box 11)
  - T - Z. (Box 12)
  - Clippings re various issues and items re "not completed projects." (Box 13, Box 14)
  - Conservation award presented to Randall Henderson, 1963 (Box 205, Folder 3)
- Brower Controversy
  - Collection of papers dealing with the Brower Controversy Loose / less than full. (Box 143)
- Chapter newsletters and other publications.
  - 1982 (Box 20)
    (Donated February 1983)
  - 1983 (Box 21)
    (Donated February 1984)
  - 1984 (Box 22)
    (Donated February 1985)
  - 1985 (Box 23)
    (Donated March 1986)
  - 1987 (Box 24)
    (Donated January 1988)
  - 1986 (Box 25)
  - 1988 (Box 26)
  - 1989 (Box 27)
  - Include additions donated January 1981. (Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18)
  - 1981 (Box 19)
    (Donated February 1982)
- Chapters and Territorial Groups
  - Chapter member activity. (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - Angeles: SMMTF. (Box 118, Folder 13)
  - Eastern Sierra Nevada. (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Kern Kaweah. (Box 118, Folder 15)
  - Loma Prieta. (Box 118, Folder 16)
  - Mother Lode. (Box 118, Folder 17)
  - Los Padros. (Box 118, Folder 18)
  - Redwood. (Box 118, Folder 19)
  - San Diego[?]. (Box 118, Folder 20)
  - San Francisco Bay. (Box 118, Folder 21)
  - San Gorgonio. (Box 118, Folder 22)
  - Sta Lucia. (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Tehipile. (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Toiyabe. (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Ventana. (Box 119, Folder 4)
- County and City Parks
  - County and city parks (general). (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Elysian. (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Griffith park. (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Hazard Park. (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - Balboa Park. 18/54-19/76. (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Catalina Island. (Box 85, Folder 2)
- Desert
  - Desert newspaper clippings. (Box 112, Folder 1)
- Energy
  - Energy (Box 96, Folder 6-7)
- Energy and Economics
  - Energy and Economics (Box 96, Folder 8)
- Enviromental Quality Board
  - Enviromental Quality Board material (Box 41, Box 42, Box 43)
- Files
  - Set of Southern Sierran (Set no.3), May 1946 complete through August 1972. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Angeles Chapter Anti-litter Committee Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers of Dorothy Leavitt Pepper. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Contains old songbook: "Songs for the Camapfire."
  - Personal Papers of Paul W. Somers., 1935-1937. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Regards organization work for Pacific Crest Trail System
  - Diary of Clara Lehner, containing account and photographs of a Sierra Club Outing, July 10-31, 1929. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Nathan C. Clark's files as a member of the Board of Directors: minutes, briefs, correspondence and related papers, 1953-1968. (Box 3)
    Some annotated by NCC.
  - Nathan C. Clark's Sierra Club Foundation files: minutes, procedures manual, grant descriptions and numbers, 1967-1977 (Box 4)
  - Richard Searle's files as an Executive Committee member, and Secretary, 1965-1968. (Box 5)
- Frank Sanborn Collection
  - Sierra Peaks
    - SPS Archives (Box 175, Folder 1)
      1 CD.
      Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    - SPS Emblem #77, 1 September 1963 (Box 175, Folder 2)
    - SPS Plaque dedicated to Chairman, 1956 (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - 35mm Color Slides, 1957 - 1963 (Box 175, Folder 4)
      86 photos with captions written by Frank Sanborn
    - Sierra Club Schedules (1 of 9) (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (2 of 9), 1960 - 1965 (Box 176, Folder 2)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (3 of 9), 1960 - 1965 (Box 176, Folder 3)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (4 of 9) (Box 176, Folder 4)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (5 of 9) (Box 176, Folder 5)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (6 of 9), 1950 - 1960 (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (7 of 9), 1950 - 1960 (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (8 of 9) (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - Sierra Club Schedules (9 of 9) (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - Black and White Prints, 1950 - 1954 (Box 189, Folder 1)
    - Black and White Prints (II), 1950 - 1954 (Box 189, Folder 2)
    - Black and White Prints (Box 189, Folder 3)
    - Kodacolor Prints (Box 189, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Color Prints, 1987 - 1992 (Box 189, Folder 5)
    - Slide Boxes (No. 1 - 4), 1958 - 1959 (Box 189, Folder 6)
      Viewers: Please take care to preserve the chronological order of the slides.
- Land Use Planning: Forests, Mining
  - 16/60a-16/68. Forests, mining 16/63. (Box 59, Folder 1)
- Land Use Planning: Forests, Oceans and Estuaries, Parks
  - Forest Fire management and fire ecology. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Forests, effect of air pollution. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Forests (national)--land sales. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Forest practices / Forest management (80-82, 77-79). (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - 74-76, 70-73, 44-69. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - 16/47a-48. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - 16/49 - 16/51. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - 16/51-51a. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - 16/51-b. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - 16/51-16/52. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - 16/52-16/53. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - 16/53e-16/56. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - 16/56-16/56f. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - 16/56f-16/57b. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - 16/57c-16/57k. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - 16/58-16/58e. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - 16/59-16/59a. (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - 16/59b-16/59e. (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - 16/59f-16/60. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - 17/1-17/6. Also 17/9a-18/1. (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - 17/7-18/7. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - National parks 18/8a-18/16. (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Devils postpile, National Monument. (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Glacier National Park. (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Grand Canyon, National Monument. (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Great Basin National Park. (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Haleakala, National Monument. (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Hell's Canyon. (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - NRA 18/8a-18/9. (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Joshua Tree National Monument. (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Death Valley (various). (Box 75, Folder 2-3)
  - Lake Mead. (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Lassen National Park. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Mineral King (various) 18/21a. (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - 18/21b-m. Mineral King (maps and various). (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - 18/21n-g. Mineral King (various). (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - 18/21h-18/22b. Mineral King (various). (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Mojave national park [D.H. has folder]. (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - National Monuments (general). (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - National urban parks. (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978. 18/22-18/27. (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Northern Cascades National Park. (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Pinnacles National Monument. (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Orange Coast National Urban Park. (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Pt Reyes. (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Rainbow Bridge National Monument. (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - 18/22-18/27. Redwood National Park. (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - 18/27-18/28. Redwood National Park. (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Sta Marguerita National Rec Proposal. (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - 18/28-18/33. Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area. (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - 18/28-18/33. Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area. (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Sawtooth National Recreation Area. (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Sequoia and Kings Canyon National Park. (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Yellowstone. (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Yosemite. (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Zion National Park. (Box 82, Folder 6)
- Legislative Initiatives, 1970s
  - Energy Development, Oil & Gas. (Box 146)
  - Prop. 9. Newspaper Accounts. (Box 146)
  - Prop. 9, Related Legislative Codes. (Box 146)
  - Prop. 9, Sierra Club Pro & Con Reports, Final. (Box 146)
  - Conservation Task Force, Prop. 9, Mostly Letters. (Box 146)
  - Energy Development, Nuclear. (Box 146)
  - Air Pollution-Mobile Sources. (Box 146)
  - Air Pollution-Stationary Sources. (Box 146)
  - Nuclear Iniative-Preliminary. (Box 146)
  - Sierra Club-Nuclear. (Box 146)
  - Nuclear Iniative. (Box 146)
  - Prop. 9, Sierra Club Letters & Reports, Analysis & Comments. (Box 146)
  - Prop. 9, Legislative Comments. (Box 147)
  - Prop. 9, Post-Mortem. (Box 147)
  - Prop. 9, Comments & Analysis, Non-Sierra Club. (Box 147)
- Loose Files [Additions]
  - Santa Barbara Information & Maps. (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Death Valley. (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Alaska. (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Yosemite Park. (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Astronomy Information. (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Desert area military operations. (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - East Mojave Monitor [newsletter]. (Box 138, Folder 7)
- Material re coastal issues 1973-1975
  - General correspondence and papers, A - P. (Box 6)
  - General correspondence and papers, R - Z (Box 7)
  - California Coastal Zone Conservation Commission: staff reports, 1973 (Box 7)
  - South Coast Regional Commission proceedings of meetings, 1974-1975. (Box 7)
    Additions donated November 1978)
  - San Diego Regional Commission minutes, 1973-1974. (Box 8)
  - California Coastal Zone Conservation Commission: staff reports, 1973 (Box 8)
  - San Diego Regional Commission minutes, 1975-1976. (Box 9)
- Mining, Real Estate
  - 16/69-16/85. Mining, real estate 16/17. (Box 60, Folder 1)
- National
  - Economics committee. (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - National Energy committee. (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Fossil fuels. (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Forest practices. (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Native American issues. (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - National land use. (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Populations. (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Public lands. (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Waste Resources. (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Wilderness. (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Wildlife and endangered species. (Box 118, Folder 11)
- National Sierra Club Papers
  - BOD (Board of Directors Minutes) (Box 142, Box 143)
  - Council (National) (Box 143)
  - Conservation Committee Minutes (Box 143)
- NCRCC
  - Other RCC's. (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous 81-84. (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Field office staff internal correspondance. (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - International. (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Midwest. (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - NW, SACTO, SE, SW. (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Perspective. (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Sierra Club national. (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - BOD organization. (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Sierra Club Council. (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Nevada Office. (Box 118, Folder 6)
- Newsletters
  - Angeles Chapter
    - Conservation Committee, July 1990 - May 1992 (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Inner City Outings, July 1991 - December 1994 (Box 149, Folder 6)
      Missing most of 1993 & 1994
    - Population Committee (Box 150, Folder 3)
      Not comprehensive, only a few issues from each year
    - 20s & 30s Singles, June/July 1991 - February/March 1994 (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Airport/Marina Group Publication, No dates available (Box 150, Folder 8)
      Only two issues
    - Rio Hondo Group (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Mule Pack Section (Box 151, Folder 4)
      Legal size
    - Natural Science Section, July/August 1991 - October 1991 (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Conservation Committee, 1990 (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Conservation Committee (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - Conservation Committee, 1988 (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - Conservation Committee, 1987 (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Conservation Committee (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Conservation Committee (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Conservation Committee, 1984 (Box 152, Folder 7)
    - Conservation Committee, 1983 (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - Conservation Committee (Box 152, Folder 9)
    - Conservation Committee (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Conservation Committee, 1980 (Box 152, Folder 11)
    - Conservation Committee, 1979 (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - Conservation Committee (Box 152, Folder 13)
    - Campaign '92 Informational (Box 153, Folder 8)
      Written by Betsy Loyless as an endorsement of Rep. George Miller (D) California, an advocate for environmental issues
    - Green Guide (Box 153, Folder 9)
      Order form for Sierra Club "Green Guide" to environmental education materials
    - Friday Evening Dinners, Schedule of Programs, July 2, 1993 - February 18, 1994 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - Santa Monica Mountains Task Force, September 1993 - September 1994 (Box 153, Folder 15)
    - Wilderness Training Committee, July 1991, January 1992, May 1993, October 1993, March 1994 (Box 153, Folder 17)
    - Waste Reduction News (Box 153, Folder 18)
    - Southern Sierran, 2000 (Box 223, Folder 8)
  - Antelope Valley Group
    - reosote Chronicle (The), September 1991 - March 1992, May 1993 - March 1994 (Box 148, Folder 4)
      Missing issues from October 1991, June/July/August 1993
  - Cabrillo Section
    - Ebbtide, July 1991 - May 1993 (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Airport/Marina Group (Box 153, Folder 7)
      Not comprehensive, only one or two issues from each year
  - Camera Committee
    - Focal Points, August 1991 - November 1993, March 1994 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      Legal size; missing one or two issues from each year
  - Crescenta Valley Group
    - Crescenta Valley (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - Four Star (The) (Box 149, Folder 5)
      Volume I, Issues I & II
  - Desert Peaks Section
    - The Desert Sage, July 1991 - March 1993 (Box 149, Folder 1)
      Not comprehensive, missing at least a dozen issues between 1991 - 1993
    - The Desert Sage / The Desert Bulletin, March 1993 - January 1994 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 264 - 253), 1998 - 1999 (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 252 - 239), 1995 - 1997 (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 238 - 229) (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 228 - 219), 1992 - 1993 (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 218 - 207), 1990 - 1992 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 206 - 190) (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 189 - 165) (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 164 - 144), 1978 - 1982 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 143 - 125), 1974 - 1978 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 124 - 103) (Box 179, Folder 5)
      The number of the last issue (No. 103) is in question
    - The Desert Sage (No. 102 - 83) (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - The Desert Sage (No. 80 - 53), 1958 - 1965 (Box 180, Folder 2)